Christopher Biemer

Backend Developer Creative Problem Solver Data Analyst Chrisbiemer.github.io/CB www.github.com/chrisbiemer chrisbiemer@ymail.com 1615 West Catalpa Avenue Chicago, Illinois 60640 (630) 699-7143

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY: Technology professional based in Chicago, Illinois with demonstrated experience designing and implementing databases, consulting businesses on how to act on data trends and bringing a creative-edge to algorithmic development.

Python, JavaScript, R, Stata, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Amazon Web Services, Node.js, Microsoft Access, React.js, Tableau, MongoDB

Education:

Loyola University Chicago | Quinlan School of Business

(August 2013 - May 2017)

Curriculum: Econometrics, Financial Analysis, Information Systems, Accounting, Strategy

Economics, BBA | Cum Laude | GPA: 3.647/4.000 | Major GPA: 3.800/4.000

Northwestern University | 24-Week Web Application Development Course (August 2017 - March 2018)

Curriculum: JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, React.js, MySQL, Python, MongoDB, Python, HTML5, CSS3*

Work Experience:

Specialdocs Consultants, LLC | Marketing & Sales Data Analyst

(April 2018 - July 2018)

- Audited extensive Quickbase databases while changing data collection processes to facilitate future analytic research initiatives.
- Worked with the Chief Executive Officer, Vice President of Sales, Marketing Director & Vice President of Public Relations to develop a Sales & Marketing dashboard tracking the effectiveness of internal and external spending efforts.
- Used Tableau, R, Python, Adobe Creative Cloud, iMovie and Microsoft Office to develop supplementary marketing materials including data visualizations, graphics, short films and mathematical estimations.

Barbara O'Brien for Denver Public Schools Board | Inside Sales Campaign Support

(October 2017 - November 2017)

- Assisted a winning campaign in encouraging a properly-educated voter turnout.
- Responsive communication across multiple platforms to plan and perfect phone call tactics.
- Data reporting in Microsoft Excel to calculate estimated turnout- and conversion-rates.

DUOS Project @ Quinlan School of Business | Paid Database Design Internship

(March 2016 – August 2016)

- Developed a relational database of the experimental components cited in published economic research journals, including databases, variables, variable values, methodologies, equations, time periods and findings.
- Communicated with management and peers to design data entries in a "quote-perfect" way that facilitated artificial intelligence applications in learning how to scan additional papers for experimental components without human involvement.
- Reviewed graduate-level computational econometric research methods involving Linear Algebra, Calculus & Statistics.

Whole Foods Market | Seafood Sales & Customer Service

(June 2014 to April 2016)

- Voted into a team in which I worked directly with management and peers to balance out department coverage, earning an increase from \$10.00/hour to \$12.00/hour across a nearly two-year tenure.
- Educated customers on the environmental- and health-conscious practices of Whole Foods Market's seafood suppliers.

Projects:

- Matrix Multiplication Calculator with Command-Line UI/UX (Python 3, Bash) [Repository: https://goo.gl/3X2To3]
- Quantitative Harmonic & Rhythmic Analysis (Microsoft Excel, Mathematics) [Sample: https://goo.gl/7zRr4f]
- Derivative & Integral Calculator with Command-Line UI/UX (Python 3, Bash) [Repository: https://goo.gl/13KfWN]
- Hokusai Memory Game, React.js-based Web Application (React.js, Bootstrap) [Live App: https://goo.gl/xDqVVL]
- Backend Developer, Game-On Pickup Sports Scheduler (MySQL, Node.js, Cookies) [Live App: https://goo.gl/d8oxUm]
- Custom Database Designs for Messaging, Purchasing & Content Sharing (ERD Plus) [Schematics: https://goo.gl/nG6ddV]
- Internet Availability vs. Art Museum Attendance (Undergraduate Econometrics Research) [Article: https://goo.gl/B8r3mF]
- Crayonbox, Event Information Web Application (Leaflet, Zomato, SVG Animation) [Live App: https://goo.gl/ddPqr9]
- Historic Art Movement-themed Trivia Game Web Application (JavaScript, Bootstrap) [Live App: https://goo.gl/m3MmjW]
- Analysis of the Creative Class in Austin, Texas (Urban Economis, Business Writing) [Sample: https://goo.gl/5CDnEJ]
- Machine Learning Algorithm Development to Predict User Credit Scores (R, Tableau) [Article: https://goo.gl/6FqX8P]
- Tableau Heat Maps for an Undisclosed Marketing Campaign in Atlanta, Georgia (Tableau) [Link: https://goo.gl/5WNhQa]
- Copywriting Sample Covering the Guttmacher Institute of Reproductive Health [Article: https://goo.gl/cBE7vR]
- Visuals for a Public Speech Covering the Surrealist Movement of Paris, France [Powerpoint: https://goo.gl/qtf741]

Extracurricular: